## **Scott Hofman**

## **Software Engineer**

Canadian Citizen - Looking to relocate to Sweden

#3 1212 7 St SW, Calgary, Canada, T2R 1A4 scott.a.hofman@gmail.com www.scotthofman.com +1 587 432 3532

## **QUALIFICATIONS SUMMARY**

A full-stack software engineer, I am a team lead at Getty Images, responsible for writing, testing, building and releasing front-end code for iStockphoto. Along with these responsibilities, I have been on an on-call rotation for two years, demonstrating an effective capability to work well under pressure. I have been programming for nearly fifteen years and maintain several side projects. In both my professional and personal projects, I constantly undertake projects in new or unfamiliar languages. I enjoy the challenge of working on scalable pages. I work on pages that receive four million unique views per week. In university, I developed a scalable website for generating Word Clouds as my dissertation project.

## HIGHLIGHTED PROJECTS

#### Add Search By Image to iStockphoto.com

January - February 2017

- Technologies Used: Angular, AWS S3, Jasmine, Teaspoon, Ruby/Rails, SCSS, JQuery
- Extended existing library to allow users to drag-and-drop/select files and upload files to the cloud, adding inline validation and tests.
- Created responsive modal to be used site-wide as a re-usable mixin.
- Adapted Javascript search functionality to use fingerprint as search parameter. Needed to maintain search functionality for three different sites.

#### **Moving Asset View Page to Getty Images**

April - November 2016

- Technologies Used: Angular, SCSS, Ruby/Rails, PHP, JQuery, Coffeescript, C#, Rspec
- Wrote logic to handle 30 unique download states, adapted responsive carousel to display similar images, and handled backwards compatibility for routing structures.
- Styled the page to be identical to previous iteration, despite different underlying HTML.
- Improved page performance page load time decreased by 50%.
- Scripted user creation to increase team productivity.

#### Port iStockphoto onto Getty Images development stack

January - March 2016

- Technologies Used: HaProxy, Ruby/Rails, Sinatra
- Implemented a load balancer to route requests from old servers to new.
- Coded proxy rules to strip iStock's country/language from URL request, redirect to appropriate Rails app, and re-append country/language for SEO.
- Developed tests to validate routing behavior for both iStock and Getty Images.

### iStockphoto CMS Implementation

March 2014 - March 2016

- Technologies Used: Autonomy TeamSite, PHP, phpunit, CSS, XML, XSLT, C#
- Designed system to fetch complete webpages, and to show fallback content on error.
- Delivered design of key pages under tight deadlines Homepage, Plugins Promo, Pricing.
- Deployed system to update prices on a per-user basis.
- Took responsibility for training individuals on CMS implementation.

#### **Update Credit Purchase Logic on iStockphoto**

June - August 2015

- Technologies Used: MySQL, RabbitMq, PHP, phpunit, Git
- Worked with legacy code to update credit expiry logic
- Wrote gueries to process and update expiry dates on all active credits.
- Deprecated a purchase flow, removing hundreds of lines of code.
- Improved dozens of unit tests decreased test suite runtime by 16%.

#### Allow Anonymous Users to Purchase on iStockphoto December 2014 - March 2015

- Technologies Used: PHP, Zend, Jasmine, Grunt, MySQL, Angular, phpunit
- Refactored checkout process to allow anonymous users to purchase items.
- Increased testability of the checkout application.
- Developed a session-based cart for anonymous users, with capability to transfer to database for checkout.

#### **Rytmos** - Independant Android Game

lune - August 2012

- Technologies Used: C#, Unity, Photoshop, SQLite, C, Java, SVN
- Developed core game mechanics and setup database for tracking player scores.
- Assisted with art creation, sound processing and marketing.
- Released on Google Play within three-month deadline, using rapid prototyping.

# **Dissertation - Create Interactive Group of Word Clouds** September 2012 - April 2013

- Technologies Used: Javascript, Java, Ruby/Rails, CSS
- Refined algorithm for creating word clouds.
- Created and deployed scalable web application.

#### **ADDITIONAL SKILLS**

- Communication Responsible for delivering progress and feature updates to company for asset detail project. Demos project work on a monthly basis to technical group
- Hackathon Participation Setup Gitlab build server to deploy Docker instance to DC/OS for team to use multiple image library APIs. Wrote code to tag images with keywords.
- Mobile Application Development Writing an Android application in Java to track speed of exercise bike and control TV based around maintaining a minimum speed

#### **EMPLOYMENT**

iStockphoto LP / Getty Images

July 2014 - Present

Software Engineer

**Rytmos** 

Basewarp

August 2013 - December 2013

Contract Software Developer

June 2012 - August 2012

Cofounder, Software Developer, Designer

#### **EDUCATION**

**University of Edinburgh**, Edinburgh, UK *BEng in Software Engineering with First Class Honours* 

Sept 2009 – July 2013